<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Get Started on</title><link>https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/</link><description>Recent content in Get Started on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/introduction/</guid><description>Pomsky is a language that compiles to regular expressions. It is currently in an alpha stage and will likely change in the next few releases.
Usage #Pomsky can be used with a CLI, a JavaScript plugin, or a Rust macro. See installation instructions.
You should also enable Unicode support in your regex engine if it isn&amp;rsquo;t supported by default. See instructions.
Summary #
👉 Here you can see all the features at a glance.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/quick-start/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/quick-start/</guid><description>Playground #Using the playground is the easiest and most convenient way to get started using pomsky. It supports syntax highlighting and shows errors directly in your code.
CLI #The CLI allows you to compile pomsky expressions to regexes in the command line.
Use pre-built binaries #Binaries are available for Windows, Linux and macOS. Download them from the releases page.
Use AUR package #On Arch Linux, you can use the AUR package with</description></item><item><title>Enable Unicode Support</title><link>https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/enable-unicode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pomsky-lang.org/docs/get-started/enable-unicode/</guid><description>Pomsky has good Unicode support, but you might still have to enable Unicode support in your regex engine. This document explains how to do that for various regex engines.
If some information here is missing, outdated or needs clarification, I would greatly appreciate your help! You can edit this file on GitHub.
Rust #The Rust regex crate is Unicode-aware by default. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing you need to do.
JavaScript #In JavaScript, set the u flag, for example /[\w\s]/u.</description></item></channel></rss>